<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Stochastics on Chris Miles</title>
    <link>/~miles/tags/stochastics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Stochastics on Chris Miles</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/~miles/tags/stochastics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The true jump method</title>
      <link>/~miles/post/true-jump-method/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/~miles/post/true-jump-method/</guid>
      <description>A while ago, I learned a numerical recipe for simulating state-dependent jump processes from this paper by Romain Veltz. After some digging, this book by Graham and Talay seems to introduce the method. It’s a cute trick that even my advisor was excited by, so I figured it seemed like a nice short thing to share.
Setup Suppose we have some switching process \(X_t\), which between jump events evolves via \[\begin{equation} \frac{\mathrm{d}}{\mathrm{d}t} X_t = F(X_t).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diffusing diffusivities, stochastic subordination</title>
      <link>/~miles/post/diff-diff/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/~miles/post/diff-diff/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I’ll discuss an idea emerging in the statistical physics community that attempts to resolve some unexplained observations of motion of single particles.1
Anomalous yet Brownian The motivation is as follows: suppose we observe two particles and keep track of their trajectory, as seen in Figure 1.
  {&#34;x&#34;:{&#34;url&#34;:&#34;/~miles/post/2017-10-19-diff-diff_files/figure-html//widgets/widget_fig1.html&#34;,&#34;options&#34;:{&#34;xdomain&#34;:&#34;*&#34;,&#34;allowfullscreen&#34;:false,&#34;lazyload&#34;:false}},&#34;evals&#34;:[],&#34;jsHooks&#34;:[]} Figure 1: Two (simulated) trajectories of particles undergoing what seems to be classical Brownian motion (diffusion).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stochastic limits, part 2: tails, memory, and the Joseph and Noah effects</title>
      <link>/~miles/post/stoch-lim-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/~miles/post/stoch-lim-part-2/</guid>
      <description>In the last post, we discussed what happens to the sum \[\begin{equation} \lim_{N\to\infty} S_N - \mu N, \qquad S_N := \sum_{i=1}^{N} X_i, \end{equation}\] with \(X_i\) drawn from some “nice” distribution with \(\mu := \mathbb{E}[X_i]\). In this scenario, \(\mathbf{S}_N(t) \to \mathbf{B}(t)\), Brownian motion. For this discussion, we’ll have to state a little more explicitly what we mean by “nice.” The two big features we needed are
finite (first two) moments, i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stochastic limits, part 1: CLT,  Donsker’s FCLT</title>
      <link>/~miles/post/stoch-lim-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/~miles/post/stoch-lim-part-1/</guid>
      <description>In the ever-growing list of talks I’ve suffered through, I’ve noticed a bizarre trend in many given by mathematicians considered “rockstars”: half the talk consists of rambling about old, obscure books in their field. I’m honestly not sure if this is simply because they can get away with it because they’re already famous, or because arcane tomes are a genuinely good source of information. I’m operating under the latter assumption.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>